SY LE SF BAY AREA, CA 408-216-3428 LE.NGUYEN.SY@GMAIL.COM SYNLE.GITHUB.IO LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SYLE1021

SUMMARY

I'm Sy Le, a software engineer with 11+ years of experience developing web applications at Linkedin, Salesforce, and Yahoo. Throughout my career, I had built solutions for CRM, Marketing Automation, e-commerce and monitoring platform. My specialty is JavaScript / React on the front end and Node JS / Express on the backend. But I believe in continuous learning and willing to learn anything to get the job done.

EDUCATION

Master Of Science in Software Engineering

San Jose State University Graduated 2019

· Graduated with Specialization in Cloud & Mobile Computing.

Bachelor Of Science in Computer Science

San Jose State University Graduated 2011

• Graduated Cum Laude with Specialization in Computer Graphics.

EXPERIENCE

Staff Software Engineer @ Linkedin

Sunnyvale, CA

03/2020 - Present

- · Providing guidance for core Front End initiatives, UI framework, and Azure DevOps CI & CD pipeline for Linkedin EPE.
- · Working on **Linkedin Support Portal** that manages customers' chats and offline cases on Microsoft Dynamics365 CRM using C#, .NET Core, React and Microsoft Fluent UI.
- Redesigned modern codebase Sendbloom with TypeScript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, Redis and MySQL.

Senior Software Engineer @ Linkedin

Sunnyvale, CA

05/2017 - 02/2020

- Software Engineer for Linkedin Enterprise Learning and Enterprise Productivity Engineering using JavaScript, Ember, React, Node.js, Java, Spring Boot, Python, Flask, MySQL, Redis and Azure.
- Full Stack Engineer Team Lead, worked on Nucleus, an end-to-end purchase flow automation with React-and-Redux Front End, and Spring Boot Back End hosted on Azure having integrations with ServiceNow and JIRA.
- Integrated Linkedin Learning with Slideshare DocViewer to allow end-to-end custom document content creation and viewing.
- Developed and Presented Room Booking Assistant (RoomBA), a bot written with Node.js and Azure Message Service Bus to intelligently book meeting rooms using attendees' locations at Linkedin GOPs Expo 2017.

Senior Member Of Technical Staff @ Salesforce

San Francisco, CA

04/2015 - 05/2017

- · Software Engineer for SalesforceIQ, and Aura using JavaScript, Angular, React, Salesforce Aura / Lightning, Node.js, Express, and Java.
- · Major contributor for SalesforceIQ Inbox, led and provided mentorship for junior members in the team of SalesforceIQ Inbox Desktop.
- Built Lightning integration that brings Inbox productivity features with Salesforce Lightning for Gmail and Outlook.
- · Prototyped Inbox Desktop Email client with React and Electron that lets you read your emails and interact with Salesforce Records.
- · Prototyped Desktop Dialer with Twilio which sales reps to communicate with customers right on the browser.
- · Won SalesforceIO Hackday Fall 2016 Most Creative with predictive email compose suggestion project.
- ·Won SalesforceIQ Hackday Spring 2017 Most heroic award with mass email project.

Tech Yahoo, Software Dev Engineer @ Yahoo Inc

Sunnyvale, CA

07/2014 - 04/2015

- · Front End Engineer for Yahoo Monitoring team, doing redesign of Yamas 2.0 Dashboard with JavaScript, Angular, Node.js and Express.
- · Within a short time, completed the redesign of Yamas which received internal Yahoo TechPulse 2014 conference award.
- · Set up CI and CD pipeline for Express Back End applications with Jenkins CI and Chef CD to streamline building and deployment.

Software Engineer @ eBay Inc

San Jose, CA

08/2013 - 07/2014

- · Software Engineer for Transaction Flow and Registration team, working with JavaScript, Java and Spring MVC Framework.
- · Implemented the responsive Guest Checkout Registration which allows users to register for new eBay account after checking out as guest.
- · Integrated Selenium UI automation to extend UI integration test coverage to iPad and iPhone using Selenium iWebDriver.

Software Engineer @ eTrigue Inc

San Jose, CA

10/2011 - 08/2013

- Full Stack Engineer for eTrigue Demand Center using JavaScript, PHP, Node.js, C#, MySQL, Cassandra and RabbitMQ.
- Owned and built core components of the eTrigue Demand Center including Prospect List, Campaign Builder, ETL Jobs for Sales Velocity/ROI reporting and extracting prospects' information from vendors such as Cisco Webex and Citrix GoToWebinar.

Software Engineer @ MTSS

San Jose, CA

08/2010 - 10/2011

• Full Stack Engineer building from scratch Clinic Tree, a clinic portal with patient record charting, appointments management and dynamic content management system using JavaScript and C# and .Net.

SIDE PROJECTS

- sqlui-native: created a cross-platform native desktop application written in Electron and React that allows you to manage a wide range of databases such as MySQL, PostgresSQL, MS SQL Server, Cassandra, MongoDB and Redis supporting Windows, Mac and Linux.
- · import-fixer: developed a npm executable module that cleans up javascript / TypeScript duplicates or unused imports in a deterministic way.
- · Rest API Decorators: a TypeScript library that make writing API Client for Nodejs and Frontend simpler inspired by Square Retrofit library
- · Note Synchronizer: a background application written in Node, Reddis, and MySQL to sync emails / attachments to Google Drive
- Sequelize ORM Decorators: a TypeScript library that simplifies Sequelize (NodeJS ORM library) schema definitions.

SKILLS

- Front End: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Reselect, React Query, Jest, Angular, Storybook, Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Puppeteer, Sinon, Axios
- · Back End: Node.js, Express, Java, Spring Boot, Maven, Mockito, Jackson, Jetty.
- Databases / Technologies: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Redis, MongoDB, Selenium, Cassandra, RabbitMQ
- Tools: Git, Docker, Vagrant, VirtualBox, NGINX, JIRA, Bash, Jenkins CI, Github Actions, Azure, AWS and SauceLabs.